And so it gives me great pleasure to introduce to you the project that I've lined up for you this week.
그래서 이번 주에 여러분께 소개할 프로젝트를 소개하게 되어 기쁘군요
And boy, is it a meaty one.
정말 두툼한 고기예요
Here it is, the capstone project of the course.
이 코스 최고의 프로젝트예요
I've called it The Price is Right.
가격 맞히기 게임이에요
It's something which brings together what we've been doing to date.
지금까지 해온 일을 하나로 묶어주는 거죠
The idea is we're going to build.
일단 집을 지을 거예요
The challenge that's been set for us is to build a platform which can look for deals being published
우리에게 주어진 과제는 인터넷에 게시된 거래를 찾고 RSS 피드를 구독할 수 있는
on the internet, subscribe to RSS feeds so it can it can spot deals that have been published.
플랫폼을 만드는 겁니다 게시된 거래를 스팟팅할 수 있도록요
When it finds a potential deal, a promising looking deal, it will read it, it will interpret it,
잠재적 거래를 찾으면 유망해 보이는 거래를요 그걸 읽고 해석해 다수의 LMS를
and it will then use a number of LMS, including the proprietary one that we built last week to make
사용합니다 지난주에 우리가 만든 소유권을 포함해서요 그게 얼마나 가치 있는지
its own estimate of how much that's worth, and if it finds a good opportunity, it will then automatically
추정하기 위해서요 그리고 좋은 기회를 찾으면 자동적으로 텍스트 메시지나
send a text message or a push notification to to you or to me telling us that there is a deal that we
푸시 알림을 여러분이나 제게 보냅니다 우리가 알아야 할 거래가 있다고 알려주는 거죠
should know about and it will run autonomously all the time, just sitting around running in the background,
자율적으로 항상 실행될 겁니다 백그라운드에서 실행되는 거죠 가끔
and every so often you will get a push notification to say there's a new deal that's been posted online,
푸시 알림을 받게 됩니다 온라인에 포스팅된 새 거래가 있다는 거죠 모델이 이 가격이
where the model has decided that this price is a really great price because the item should cost a lot
정말 좋다고 결정하는 거죠 아이템은 훨씬 더 비싸야 하니까요
And I hope you agree, if we can pull that off, if we can build that platform, we've built something
동의하시길 바랍니다 우리가 해낼 수 있다면 플랫폼을 구축할 수 있다면 특별한
special that is an advanced platform.
걸 구축한 겁니다 고급 플랫폼이죠
It's something which brings together a lot of different bits of functionality, and it's something that
다양한 기능성 요소들을 한데 합친 것입니다. 제가 자랑스러워할
that hopefully I will be proud of, and I hope you'll be proud of it too, when it's built.
만한 것이었으면 좋겠고 여러분도 자랑스러워 하실 수 있었으면 좋겠어요.
There are going to be seven agents.
요원은 7명이 될 거예요
I already said it, but I say it again.
아까도 말했지만 다시 말할게요
Seven agents are going to collaborate.
7명의 요원이 협력할 거예요
Um, not all of them are built on LMS.
전부 LMS에 설치된 건 아니에요
Some of them are more sort of Python processes, but they're sort of seven pieces to the puzzle that
파이썬 을 사용하는 과정도 있지만 퍼즐의 일곱 조각 같은 것들이 서로 협력하고
are collaborating.
있어요
We will use GPT four or GPT four mini to take information from RSS feeds and parse it and understand
GPT 4, 또는 GPT for 미니를 이용해 RSS 피드에서 정보를 취하고 분석하고 이해한
it and turn it into something which is a potential deal.
후 잠재적 거래로 바꿀 거예요
We will use our frontier busting model that outperforms GPT four.
개척지 급습 모델을 쓸 거예요 GPT 4보다 뛰어나죠
And Claude will use it to estimate how much things are worth.
클로드는 그걸로 물건의 가치를 추정할 거예요
But that's not all.
그게 다가 아니에요
We're going to use other models as well.
다른 모델도 사용할 거예요
We are going to build another Rag pipeline, another rag based model.
또 다른 래그 파이프라인을 만들 거예요 래그 기반 모델이죠
Um, but this time we're not going to use langue chain.
하지만 이번에는 랑그 체인을 쓰지 않을 거예요
We're going to roll our own.
직접 말 거예요
And it's going to be very, very easy.
아주 쉬울 거예요
Um, but it's going to use all 400,000 products that we, we had taken from the Amazon scrape before.
하지만 400,000가지 제품을 모두 사용할 거예요 전에 아마존 부족에게서 가져온 것들이죠
We're going to put all of them in a mega Croma database and use that to add context as part of our Rag
전부 메가 크로마 데이터베이스에 넣고 개척자 모델의 래그 파이프라인에 컨텍스트를
pipeline to a frontier model.
추가할 거예요
And you can start wondering right now, maybe you already thought of this.
이미 생각해 두신 게 아닌가 궁금해지실 거예요
Maybe you're already wondering whether or not that a a frontier model that's armed with similar prices
여러분은 이미 궁금하실 겁니다 비슷한 제품의 비슷한 가격으로 비슷한 제품을 제공하는 새로운
of similar products, whether that is going to outperform the model that we fine tuned last week.
모델이 지난주에 우리가 미세 조정했던 모델을 능가할 수 있을지 말이죠
You'll find out.
알게 될 거예요
We'll see.
두고 봐야죠
But we're going to have both models working together to try and get the best possible price.
하지만 두 모델이 협업해서 최대한 좋은 가격을 얻도록 노력할 거예요 Get up!
And another model as well as as all will be revealed.
다른 모델도 공개할 거예요
So it's going to be it's going to be a huge week.
아주 중요한 한 주가 될 거예요
The most important point, of course, was this capstone project is designed to bring it all together
가장 중요한 건 이 캡스톤 프로젝트가 모든 걸 하나로 합치는 아주 만족스러운
in a very satisfying way, in a way that's going to feel tangible and real.
방법으로 설계됐다는 거예요 손에 잡히고 진짜처럼 느껴질 수 있게요
But the real point is that this gives you a chance to revise and everything that we've learned and also
하지만 핵심은 우리가 배운 모든 것을 수정할 기회가 생긴다는
just build expertise, build experience, have some real hands on work at making production caliber
겁니다 전문성과 경험을 쌓고 생산 수준의 모델을 직접 만들 수 있죠
And that's that's really the main point of this.
그게 이 강의의 핵심이죠
We're doing it in a fun context, something that's going to actually send you push notifications when
재미있는 컨텍스트에서 하고 있어요 푸시 알림을 실제로 보낼
there's a when there's a useful product, but it's going to be about learning and solidifying the learning
뭔가가 있죠 유용한 제품이 있을 때요 하지만 학습에 관한 겁니다 지난 7주 동안
that we've done over the course of the last seven weeks.
우리가 한 학습을 확고히 하는 거죠
But let me just tell you for a moment, the architecture of our agent platform, we're going to have
잠시 말씀드리자면 에이전트 플랫폼의 아키텍처는 사용자 인터페이스를 갖게
a user interface.
될 거예요
Of course, it's going to be built in Gradio.
물론 그라디오에서 지을 거예요
It's going to be using an agent framework that we'll write, which will just be a simple kind of environment,
우리가 작성할 에이전트 프레임워크를 사용할 겁니다 단순한 종류의 환경이죠 메모리가 있어
which will have memory so that the agents can know what they've recommended in the past, and it will
에이전트는 과거에 권장했던 걸 알 수 있어요 로깅 같은 것도 지원하고요 그래서
support things like logging, so we can understand what's going on in our framework.
프레임워크에서 무슨 일이 벌어지는지 알 수 있죠
There will be an agent responsible for planning.
계획을 담당하는 요원이 있을 거예요
It's going to be coordinating activities across the other agents.
다른 요원들 간의 활동을 조율하는 거죠
And then we'll have these agents.
그럼 에이전트들이 생기죠
We'll have a scanner agent that is going to identify promising deals.
스캐너 요원이 유망한 거래를 확인할 거예요
By looking at RSS feeds.
RSS 피드를 보면요
We're going to have something I'm calling the ensemble agent, which is something there is a technical
앙상블 에이전트라는 걸 만들 거예요 기술적인 앙상블이라고
term ensemble.
부르는 거죠
When you when you bring together multiple models, this agent is going to be responsible for bringing
여러 모델을 조합할 때 이 에이전트는 제품의 가격을
together different estimating models that will estimate the price of products.
예측할 수 있는 다양한 모델을 조합하는 역할을 하죠
And we will have a messaging agent that will send us push notifications.
그리고 푸시 알림을 보내주는 메시징 에이전트가 있어요
Now this is just the high level architecture because there are more agents than this.
이건 단지 높은 수준의 아키텍처입니다 이것보다 에이전트가 더 많기 때문이죠
Because of course, that ensemble agent is itself going to collaborate with three other agents.
앙상블 에이전트 자체가 다른 세 명의 에이전트와 협업하게 되니까요
That will be our three estimating agents.
그게 우리 요원 3명이 될 거요
But I'm not showing them on this diagram because that would be too cluttered.
하지만 이 다이어그램에선 안 보여줄 거예요 너무 어수선해질 테니까요
But I will do, I'm sure, in the future when we get there.
하지만 언젠가는 꼭 할 거예요 get get get it
So this is the high level architecture to give you a sense of what we're going to build.
우리가 뭘 만들 건지 감을 잡기 위한 고급 아키텍처예요
And for today, we're going to focus on just one of these.
오늘은 이 중 하나에 집중할 거예요
And we're not going to look much at this architecture.
이 아키텍처는 많이 보지 않을 거예요
We're just going to be talking about taking the model we built last time and putting it up on the internet
지난 시간에 만든 모델을 인터넷에 올리는 것에 대해 얘기할 겁니다 Modal이라는
using this wonderful service called modal.
멋진 서비스를 이용해서요
Just before we talk about modal, one more thing I wanted to mention that as we're moving now towards
모드 얘기를 하기 전에 한 가지 더 언급하고 싶은 게 있어요 이제 더 진지한 코드를 작성하는
writing more serious code, JupyterLab is a wonderful platform for being iterative and experimental
쪽으로 나아가고 있으니 JupyterLab은 훌륭한 플랫폼이에요 반복적이고 실험적이며
and quickly turning out different solutions.
다양한 솔루션을 빠르게 내놓을 수 있죠
But as as we move along the path from R&amp;D into something which is ready to be productionized, there
하지만 연구 개발에서 생산 준비가 된 제품으로 발전할 때 코딩에
are some aspects of the coding that will be changing.
몇 가지 변화가 있을 거예요
For a start, I'm going to start to have type hints in some of the code.
우선, 코드에 힌트를 입력해 보도록 하죠
Maybe something that you're super familiar with already.
이미 아주 익숙한 것일 수도 있죠
If not, I'll explain it and it will.
안 되면 제가 설명할게요
You'll see why.
이유를 알게 될 거예요
And it's something which is a good, best practice when building this kind of production caliber code.
이런 생산 규격 코드를 만들 때 좋은 최선의 관행이죠
Uh, also going to be writing some more comments.
댓글도 더 달 거예요
It's something that when you've got a nice Jupyter notebook and you've got like lots of time to put
Jupyter 노트북이 있으면 텍스트나
text and stuff and explain it, maybe you don't need quite the same kind of commenting approach, but
설명을 넣을 시간이 많죠 주석 처리 방식은 다를지 몰라도
now, at least at the at the method at the function level will put comments in there.
적어도 함수 수준의 메서드에서 주석을 달아요
And logging is a good thing to do as well, and we will do that.
로깅도 좋은 일이고 앞으로도 그럴 거예요
Now there's one other thing which is a very good best practice, which is to write unit tests.
다른 것도 있어요 아주 최선의 관행으로 단위 테스트를 작성하는 거죠
Uh, it's very important, of course, to write good unit tests for code that's going into production.
프로덕션으로 가는 코드에 대해 좋은 단위 테스트를 작성하는 건 물론 아주 중요하죠
And I'm not going to be doing that because I'm a cowboy.
전 카우보이라서 그런 짓은 안 해요
Uh, and, uh, yeah, I certainly should do that.
네, 당연히 그래야죠
But what I will say is that it's a great exercise.
하지만 좋은 운동이라고 말씀드릴 수 있어요
Uh, should you wish to go in and write unit tests behind some of the code that we are productionizing.
우리가 제작하고 있는 일부 코드 뒤에서 단위 테스트를 작성하고 싶다면요
That will be wonderful.
그럼 정말 좋죠
I hugely appreciate it.
정말 감사해요
And if you then wanted of course to do a git push, I will merge it in with delight and will give you,
물론 Git push를 원하신다면 기쁘게 합병해 단위 테스트를 작성하는 데에
of course, full attribution and credit for writing the unit tests, which is something that certainly
대한 어휘 기여도와 크레딧을 모두 알려드리겠습니다 당연히 제가
I should I should be doing.
해야 할 일이죠
Um, and it's a very much a good best practice.
최선의 관행이라고 할 수 있죠
Okay.
네
Uh, the, the brings me to, to introducing modal, which is the platform that we're going to be using
모듈을 소개하게 됐네요 오늘 사용할 플랫폼이죠
Uh, modal, uh, a platform which allows us to run code remotely on a server, and you only pay for
모달은 서버에서 원격으로 코드를 실행할 수 있는 플랫폼으로 사용 시간당만
the time that you use.
지불할 수 있죠
It's a very powerful platform.
아주 강력한 플랫폼이죠
It's it's become heavily used in the AI world for deploying production models.
인공지능 세계에서 프로덕션 모델 배포에 많이 사용되고 있죠
Um, but it can also be used just for, for for many different purposes, just for CPU usage to deploy
하지만 다양한 목적에 사용될 수도 있어요 CPU 사용이나 클라우드에
any function onto the cloud, as we will see.
어떤 함수든 배포하는 데요
So without further ado, in the next video, we're going to go to modal and give it a try.
그럼 지체 없이 다음 비디오에선 모듈로 가서 시도해 보죠
I'll see you there.
거기서 봐요